tripzen.com 2010-05-22

# Privacy Policy - TripZen

_**Data We Collect Automatically**

As part of our servers' normal operations, we log your IP address and referring/destination URLs. We use this data, as well as other server usage data, to analyze site and user behavior, improve the site, troubleshoot technical problems, resolve disputes, address complaints and generate reports of aggregated activity that we share with others.

We and our third party vendors (such as our web analytics service provider) may use cookies and web beacons to analyze site usage, improve the site, target ads, store your preferences/passwords (if you've registered), personalize your experience (including tracking your site usage to do so) and generate reports of aggregated activity that we share with others. You must accept cookies to access tripzen.com as a registered user or to save trips as an unregistered user (if you're unregistered, any saved trips will not be accessible in a subsequent session).

**COOKIES/THIRD PARTY TRACKING**

A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user's computer for record-keeping purposes. We use cookies on this site. We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our site.

We use both session ID cookies and/or persistent cookies. We use session cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site. A session ID cookie expires when you close you browser. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser's "help" file or "privacy" menu.

We use cookies to track your session to understand if you have visited us before. Sometimes we use Persistent cookies to remember any information you may have provided on a previous visit so that you don't have to enter that information in again. Persistent cookies also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site.

**Other Data Collection**

We may get data from or about you in other ways not specifically described in this statement. For example, you might contact Customer Service, or we may get a third party complaint about you. We handle this data like other business records.

**Data Changes**

To the extent we permit you to modify or delete your data or Content, we usually update our live databases immediately, but some data may update more slowly, and some old data may remain indefinitely in our archives and records. Also, we may be unable to propagate changes to partners who receive your data or content.

**Contractors/Service Providers**

Third party contractors may have access to our databases. Usually these contractors sign a standard confidentiality agreement.

Some of our site's functionality (web analytics, website hosting, marketing services) may be operated by third party service providers, and in the course of providing this functionality, these service providers may obtain some of your personal data from you directly or transferred from us to facilitate your usage of this service. Usually we require these providers to use and disclose your personal data only as necessary to perform their services.

Third party ad servers may place or recognize a cookie and, using the cookie or otherwise, collect and use data from your visits to this and other websites to serve ads to you.

**Government Relations and Lawsuits**

We may share your data with any parent company, subsidiaries, joint ventures, other entities under a common control or third party acquirers. We expect these other entities will honor this statement. Also, we may allow a potential acquirer or merger partner to review our databases, although we would restrict their use and disclosure of this data during the diligence phase.

We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our Web site.

**Communicating with Other Users**

You may not collect (manually or in an automated manner) other users' personal data (including email addresses) from the site. **Children**

If you are 13 and under, do not use the site or provide any data to us. **Blogs**

If you use a bulletin board, blog, or similar service on the tripzen.com site, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of this site, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in this manner.

We welcome suggestions on how to improve our service for you. Please email us your feedback - the good, the ugly, the things we should add and what needs to be fixed! We appreciate your input.

**CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY**

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make significant material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, and other places we deem appropriate, including a prominent notice on our home page. 

_
